(Syncro: F.B Cavalcante)
Greyhound Seven to Trap One.
灰狗七号呼叫陷阱一号
Proceeding as scheduled.
按计划推进
Should reach checkpoint seven
at oh four fifty. Over.
应该会在04:50达到七号检查站，完毕
Understood. Out.
收到。挂了
Talkative, aren't they?
他们话真多，是不？
Bloody hell.
要命
Greyhound Seven to Trap One. Over.
灰狗七号呼叫陷阱一号。完毕
Greyhound Seven to Trap One.
Come in please. Over.
灰狗七号呼叫陷阱一号，请回话，完毕
What the hell's that?
那是什么鬼？
Greyhound Seven to Trap One.
Obstruction on road.
灰狗七号呼叫陷阱一号，发现前方有路障
Please advise. Over.
请给出建议，完毕
Another cock-up.
又搞砸了
Just in case.
以防万一
Mike, I think there's someone here
round the back of the truck.
Mike，我觉得卡车后面有什么人
Mike.
Mike﻿
Dave!
Dave!﻿
Don't move.
别动
Don't move or I fire.
别动，否则我开枪了
Auton 三部曲
第二集 圣天诺岛
Congratulations, Colonel Wilson.
恭喜，Wilson上校
It is regrettable.
令人遗憾
It is, Colonel Wilson,
的确是，Wilson 上校
a balls-up of the most
staggering magnitude.
事态从没这么严重过
Doctor Arnold.
Doctor Arnold.﻿
- What's going on?
- It seems we've lost the Autons.
- 怎么回事？  - 看来我们的 Autons 弄丢了
What? How?
什么？怎么弄丢的？
It was a covert operation.
这是一次秘密行动
An unmarked vehicle.
没有标志的车辆
No escort.
没有护卫
What, a lorry load of Autons?
什么？一卡车的Auton？
I thought they'd all been incinerated.
我还以为它们早被焚毁了
That was our recommendation two years ago.
那还是我们两年前的建议
Someone, apparently, had a different idea.
某个人，显然有不同的想法
They were being transported to
a classified location
它们是被转移去一个机密地点
for further research.
以做进一步研究
Further?
进一步？
We spent six months dissecting one.
我们用了六个月才分解了一个
We made a full report.
还写了完整的报告
So how do you propose
to get them back, Colonel?
那你建议怎么把他们找回来，上校？
Back from where?
从哪儿找回来？
Look, what exactly happened?
嘿，到底发生了什么？
We're not exactly sure.
我们也不是太清楚
I sent a back-up unit immediately,
我立即派去了一队后援
but when they arrived
there was no sign of the truck.
但他们到达的时候，没有卡车的影子
We've given the civilian authorities
a description, the number plate
我们已经给了当地政府一份描述和车牌号
and orders not to approach,
还让他们不要接近
but as yet we've heard nothing.
但目前为止我们还没听到任何消息
In short, Colonel Wilson,
简单地说，Wilson上校
you've lost a bunch of
deadly alien killing machines.
你弄丢了一堆致命的外星杀人机器
Lockwood?
Lockwood?﻿
Lockwood, are you ready yet?
Lockwood，你准备好了吗？
Yes.
是的
Yes, just coming.
是的，就来了
You know, I was just beginning to hope
that our escaped Nestene creature from the warehouse
跟你说，我倒是期望我们那个从仓库逃走的 Nestene 怪物...
might just have curled up and died somewhere.
可能龟缩起来死在某个地方了
Are we assuming it's behind all this?
我们这是觉得它是这次的幕后黑手么？
Reclaiming it's minions?
重新召集它的喽啰？
Possibly, but how did it
know where to find them?
有可能，但它怎么知道到哪里去寻找它们？
Maybe they just came into range by chance?
也许它们只是恰好跑到它的地盘了？
You all right, Lockwood?
你没事吧，Lockwood？
Sorry, Sal.
抱歉，Sal
I haven't been sleeping too well lately.
我最近一直睡得不太好
Right, Colonel.
好了，上校
I take it you're up to speed
on the whole Auton issue, yes?
我觉得你在这次 Auton 事件上动作还是挺快的，对吧？
Nestene energy unit reactivation
at the warehouse two years ago.
Nestene 能量体两年前在仓库重新被激活
Auton assumes the likeness of
senior archivist Graham Winslet,
Auton 认定是那个高级保管员 Graham Winslet 的复制品...
absorbs two energy units,
吸收了两个能量体
attempts a few faltering
steps at world domination,
试图统治世界但步履蹒跚
then reconstitutes into a blob and scarpers
when the odd on success start to look bad.
在胜算变小之后，重组为一团浆糊逃走了
I've read the file.
我读过这份档案
You must understand that
I'm not here to tread on anybody's toes.
你必须明白, 我不是来踩任何人的脚趾的
(到xx的地盘上惹事)
But I do have my orders.
但我确实有我的命令
Direct from Geneva.
直接来自日内瓦
I have my own team, and I've been appointed
head of this investigation.
我自己有团队，而且我被任命为这次调查的负责人
Why?
为什么？
That's your signature.
那是你的签名
On a transportation docket
一份运输备案目录
for all artefacts coded
triple A stroke RH stroke 2961.
针对所有编号为 AAA/RH/2961 的物品
You ordered the relocation of those Autons.
是你下令转运那些 Auton 的
Geneva has ordered that you,
Lockwood, join us.
日内瓦已经命令你，Lockwood，跟我们一起
Your role will be to provide
any specialist information...
你的职责将是提供任何专业信息...
...my own scientific adviser may need access to
...如果我的科学顾问需要这些信息的话
I want the exclusion of my containment team
from this investigation
如果我的小组被这次调查排除在外
- on the record. Colonel.
- Of course.
- 我要求将此情况记录在案，上校  - 当然
And I insist that Doctor Arnold
accompanies me.
而且我坚持让 Arnold 博士陪着我
Her work in the field of
Nestene technology is unparalleled.
她在 Nestene 技术领域的工作是无人能比的
That won't be necessary.
那就没有必要了
The car's waiting. We're late.
车在等着，我们已经晚了
Thank you, Colonel.
谢谢你，上校
I'll be with you in a moment.
我很快过来找你
Did you issue that order?
是你签发的命令吗？
No.
不是
Something's going on.
这里有事
But what?
但是什么呢？
What are you going to do?
你打算怎么办？
Obey orders.
服从命令
Have you got one of these, Sal?
你有一个这个吧，Sal ？
Ramsay!
Ramsay!﻿
It's nice to see one friendly face at least.
真好，至少还能见到一个友善的面孔
You two know each other, then.
看来你们俩相互认识
Yes, sir.
是的，长官
I was assigned to the original
warehouse containment team.
当初我被派到了仓库遏制组
Any reports on the missing truck?
有关于失踪卡车的报告吗
Not as yet, sir, but tracks suggest
it went back the way it came.
还没有，长官。但轮胎痕迹显示它从来路返回了
- It's good to see you again, Ramsay.
- And you, sir.
- 很高兴再次见到你，Ramsay  - 见到你也是，先生
Are Doctor Arnold  and
Doctor Matthews still with you?
Arnold 博士和 Matthews 博士都还跟你在一起吗？
Dan's been digging up alien artefacts
in Africa for the last six months,
Dan 在非洲挖外星人遗迹挖了六个月了
but Sal's still putting up with me.
但 Sal 还得忍受我
Why isn't she here with you?
她怎么没跟你一起过来？
This is Wilson's show.
这次是 Wilson 的主场
(?) not good enough for you.
There was something in it.
里面有某种东西
Brilliant.
高见
Something... powerful.
某种...强大的东西
Something alive.
某种活着的东西
And how did you deduce that,
young lady?
你是怎么推断出来的，小姐？
Lockwood, this is Natasha Alexander,
my scientific advisor.
Lockwood, 这是 Natasha Alexander, 我的科学顾问
Really.
真的？
Well?
怎样？
I felt it.
我感觉到的
So did you, didn't you.
你也能，对不？
This is Lockwood.
这是 Lockwood
Priority code 8954B.
优先代码8954B
Relay me to containment HQ, please.
请帮我转接总部遏制组
Morning, Sal.
早上好，Sal
Hi. How's it going?
嗨，进展怎么样？
Thought you might have gone back to bed.
还以为你可能已经回去睡觉了
What have you got for me?
你有什么需要给我的？
I'm scanning some kind of sheet
left at the scene of the crime.
我正在扫描案发现场留下的某张布单
Are you getting this?
你能收到这个吗？
Yes, receiving your transmission.
Just cross-referencing.
能，正在接收你传过来的信号，正在交叉对比
Oh, match's up.
哦，有匹配了
Trace of radiation, typical of
Nestene energy readings.
有辐射痕迹，典型的 Nestene 能量读数
Thought so.
猜就是
Ramsay, have a sample of this sheet
Ramsay，这个布单取个样本
sent back to Sal for analysis.
送回去给 Sal 去分析
Sergeant Ramsay says hello, by the way, Sal.
顺便，Ramsay 中士跟你打招呼呢
Hello, Sal?
哈罗，Sal？
So he does.
也问他好
Hello, James.
你好，James
Sir.
是
Let me know when you've got something, Sal.
如果你发现什么就告诉我，Sal
Will do. Bye.
好的，再见
Sorry, old chap.
抱歉，老家伙了
Can't work without back-up.
没有支援就干不了活
Hope you don't mind.
期望你不要介意
What's your assessment?
你的评估结果是怎样？
Nestene energy unit put here by someone.
有人在这里放置了 Nestene 能量体
Energy unit activates Autons in truck.
能量体被卡车里面的 Auton 激活了
Autons kill your men...
Auton 杀了你的人...
And drive off in truck.
然后开着卡车走了
- Where to?  - Well...
- 去了哪儿？  - 这个...
If we can find out where the sheet's from,
如果我们能搞明白这张布单来自哪儿
we may find out where the energy unit came from,
我们也许能找到能量体的来源
and perhaps where the Autons have gone.
或许也能找到 Auton 都去了哪里
Not necessarily.
不一定
No, not necessarily, Colonel.
的确，不一定，上校
But since your truck seems to have vanished
off the face of the Earth,
但既然你的卡车似乎是从地球表面上消失了
I've resorted to grasping at straws.
我就不得不抓住每根稻草了
Who do you think put the
energy unit there?
你觉得是谁把能量体放在那里了？
What a bizarre question, young lady.
这是一个多么奇怪的问题啊，小姐
If I knew that, I wouldn't be groping around here.
我要是知道那个，就不会在这里摸索了
Well, if you have any more flashes
of insight, do let me know.
好吧, 如果你有更多的灵感, 一定要告诉我
Come on, Corporal. Shift it.
快点，下士。走吧
You knew that energy unit had been
here before you checked.
你在检查之前就知道那个能量体当时是在这里
Oh, yes?
噢，是吗？
And how long have you been psychic?
而你成为一个通灵者有多久了？
Only since birth.
生下来才当上
So you read my mind.
所以你读过我的思维了
No.
没有
It was written all over your face.
都写在你的脸上呢
I think I'll wait in the car.
我想我还是去车里等
Will everything be all right
now they've arrived?
现在他们来了，一切都会好起来吗？
Yes, of course it will, Daron.
是的，当然会，Daron
What did you want to see me about, Vicar?
你要见我做什么，Vicar？
Daron... you were always the first.
Daron...你一直都是第一个
You were always the one
with the most fervour.
你一直都是最有热情的一个
You led the way for the others.
你为其他人指明方向
Am I to be the one?
我将成为那个人吗？
Yes, of course, Daron.
是的，当然，Daron
But there is one thing I must ask of you.
但有一件事我必须问你
You mean... you mean
to prove myself worthy.
你是说...是说要证明我自己的价值
Yes.
是的
Are you willing?
你愿意吗？
There's nothing I won't do.
没有什么我不会做
Good, good.
好，好
Because there are those
among our community,
因为在我们的社区里有一些...
mercifully few, I'm glad to say,
who simply do not believe.
好在不多，这点我很高兴 - 有一些人就是不相信
Oh, they'll come around, Vicar.
哦，他们会转变过来的，Vicar
- I'm sure of it.
- Time is short, Daron.
- 我很确信  - 时间很短，Daron
We have opened our hearts to these souls
and they have refused us.
我们向这些灵魂敞开了心扉, 他们拒绝了我们
That refusal has led them
straight into the hands of Satan.
这种拒绝让他们直接落入了撒旦的手中
Now that our disciples have arrived,
现在我们的门徒来了,
these servants of the devil...
这些魔鬼的仆人...
must be struck down.
必须被打倒
You know who they are, don't you?
你知道他们都是谁，对吗？
And all you have to do is think of them,
你要做的就是想着他们
and they will be delivered from evil.
他们就会被从邪恶中拯救出来
Priority code 8954B.
优先代码8954B
Secure line.
安全线路
Get me containment HQ, please.
请帮我接总部遏制组
Sal?
Sal吗?
Hi. What's up?
嗨，怎么了？
I want you to find out all you can
on Natasha Alexander.
我要你尽力找出 Natasha Alexander 的一切
- Why?  - Because...
- 为什么？  - 因为...
All I'm getting is a brick wall.
而且我能读到的是一堵砖墙
- But that's not possible.  - I know.
- 那不可能啊  - 我知道
It seems someone doesn't
want me to know about this.
看来有人不想让我知道这个
Well, there's nothing on the
standard personnel register.
反正，标准人事登记册上什么都没有
It could mean she's pretty important.
这可能意味着她相当重要
Keep looking for me...
继续帮我找...
- Would you?  - Yes.
- 行吗？  - 好
Yeah, okay.
好，OK
Oh, by the way, I may have something for you
on that sheet sample.
哦，顺便说下，那个布单采样我可能有点信息给你
Yes?
是什么？
Well, it's old, that's for sure.
哦，它很老，这是当然的
It doesn't conform to any types
manufactured within the last ten years.
它跟过去十年制造的任何类型都不相符
Oh, here we go.
噢，走起
Oh, you're not going to like this.
啊，你可能不会喜欢这个消息
Try me.
说来听听
Do you think you can work with him?
你觉得你能跟他共事吗？
Oh, yes.
噢，能
He's not going to make it easy for me,
他不会让我过得舒服
but we're going to get along just fine.
但我们会相处得不错
You are clear about your orders, Natasha?
你对自己的命令清楚吧，Natasha？
Quite clear, Colonel.
相当清楚，上校
Those are the possible points of
origin for the sheet.
这些都是那个布单的的可能出处
This is going to mean an increase
in manpower.
这将意味着需要增加人力
- Can't we narrow it down?  - Afraid not.
- 我们不能缩小范围吗？  - 恐怕不能
Those are all the locations
where that make of sheet
这些是那种布单的所有制造点
has been available within
a hundred mile radius.
这都是一百英里半径内有可能的
This is ridiculous.
这太荒谬了
Just because the sheet comes
from one area doesn't mean to say...
这布单来自哪里，并不就是说...
that's where the truck has gone.
卡车就去了哪里
No, but it's a start.
的确，不过这是个起点
And I do think you need at least to
make a start, Colonel Wilson.
而且我真的觉得你需要有个起点，Wilson上校
You've got a feeling about that sheet,
haven't you, Lockwood.
对那个布单你有某种感觉，是不是，Lookwood
No.
没有
Is someone going to drive me home?
有人开车送我回去吗？
You will give me a call,
won't you, Colonel,
你会给我电话的吧，上校
when you've come up
with something useful.
等你找到什么有用的信息的时候
I'll get in the car.
我先上车了
Again.
再次
Can't wait to get away from you, can he?
这么着急甩掉你，哈？
Give me a map.
给我一份地图
Sorry to interrupt.
抱歉打扰了
You're not going back
to containment HQ, Lockwood.
你还不能回总部遏制组，Lockwood
We're going to be working together.
我们要一起工作
It's not my choice.
不是我选择的
And it's certainly not your choice, I know.
而且肯定也不是你选择的，我知道
But you and I don't have any choice, do we?
但你跟我都没有什么选择，是吧？
That's something the
two of us have in common.
那是我们俩之间的一个共同点
They recruited me as a child.
我还是个孩子时他们就招募我了
Parents didn't want me,
couldn't cope with their psychic daughter.
父母不想要我，因为没法对付一个通灵的女儿
Couldn't lie to me, you see,
没法对我撒谎，你看
and I kept blowing all
the fuses in the house
而且我总是把家里的保险丝都弄断
every time I was smacked
and sent to my room.
每次我被揍被关入自己的房间
UNIT's been my life.
UNIT 成了我的生命
Yes, you and I have a lot in common, Lockwood.
是的，你跟我有不少共同点，Lockwood
Take a look at these locations.
看一眼这些地点
- Now what?  - Simple psychic trick.
- 那又怎样？  - 简单的通灵技巧
My party piece.
Remember what you were thinking
when you first saw that sheet.
记住你第一次看见布单的时候想到的东西
- I wasn't thinking anything.  - Remember.
- 我什么也没想  - 记住
Sentinel Island.
哨兵岛
No, not just bad dreams.
不，不只是噩梦
It's over.
结束了
Is it?
是吗？
She'll come round.
她会转变过来的
I know she will.
我知道她会的
I promise.
我保证
I swear it.
我发誓
Of course she will.
她当然会的
Why don't you go and bring her to me?
为什么你不去把她带来见我？
Go on.
去吧
That's the one.
就是那个
Seconded from Naval Intelligence boys.
从海军情报部门借调过来的
That should do the trick.
这招应该可以了
After all, we don't want to go charging in
like the D-day landings.
毕竟, 我们不想像诺曼底登陆那样冲锋
This could all be a wild goose chase.
这可能都是徒劳
It isn't.
不是
Yes, well...
是, 不过...
UNIT High Command won't
get the British government's permission for
UNIT 指挥中心没法获得英国政府的允许
a full-scale assault on Sentinel
without concrete evidence.
没有过硬的证据不能对哨兵岛发起大规模的袭击
- Did we get the AT36?
- Yes, sir.
- 我们有 AT36 吗? - 有, 长官
It's a prototype but fully tested.
还是原型, 不过全面测试过了
All the men have been issued with
the new high-powered ammunition.
所有人都给发了新的高性能弹药
No reports of any trouble from
the island, sir. Not a peep.
没有受到此岛的任何问题报告, 长官, 一点没有
All the same, we need to land
somewhere quiet, uninhabited.
都一样, 我们得找一个安静无人的地方登陆
Shouldn't be too difficult.
应该不是太难
There's only one village on the island.
这个岛只有一个村庄
Few outlying houses.
只有少数几个房子在外面
There should do.
那里应该可以
- Very well. Carry on, Sergeant.
- Sir.
- 很好, 继续吧, 中士  - 是
All right, lads, let's get a move on.
好了, 小伙子们, 开始行动吧
- Have you seen Lockwood?  - Yes.
- 你看到 Lockwood 了吗？  - 是的
Well, where is he?
那, 他在哪里？
Making a few discoveries, I should imagine.
在摸索情况, 我觉得
- Ah, Sentinel Island, Got it.
- Interesting?
- 啊, 哨兵岛, 找到了  - 有意思吧
- You into ley lines?  - What?
- 你要进入雷线？  - 什么？
Ley lines.
雷线
There's one that runs right through the island.
有一条线正穿过这个岛
(雷线: 1921年英国业余考古学家Alfred Watkins提出的假想线,
(他注意到英国一些古代遗迹都在一条直线上, 这条线被他称为＂雷线＂,
(他认为这条线具有神秘力量．也有人翻译为“灵脉”)
So there is.
原来是这样
And there are some ancient burial grounds.
那里还有一些古代墓地
You think the creature from the warehouse
is on this island?
你觉得从仓库逃出来的那个怪物现在在这个岛上？
Yes, I do.
是的, 我觉得
Anything on this Alexander woman?
有那个叫 Alexander 的女人什么信息吗？
I'm looking at her record now.
我正在看她的记录
Natasha Alexander.
Natasha Alexander.﻿
- She's a psychic.
- I know. What else?
- 她是个通灵者  - 我知道．还有什么
From the Internal Security Division.
来自内部安全部
Lockwood?
Lockwood?﻿
Yes?
怎么?
You know what the ISD do, don't you?
你知道内部安全部是干什么的吧, 是吗？
Yes.
知道
Well, are they investigating you or what?
那, 他们是在调查你什么的吗？
Perhaps.
也许吧
Lockwood, what's happened?
Lockwood, 发生了什么？
What have you, I mean, why
would they be investigating you?
你做过...我是说, 他们为什么在调查你？
- Do they know the truth about you?
- Bound to, I suppose.
- 他们知道你的真相吗？  - 应该是, 我觉得
Something's going on, isn't it?
有事情发生, 是不是
Sal, I remember.
Sal, 我想起来了
I did authorise the transport of those Autons.
的确是我授权了去转运那些 Auton
- Lockwood.  - I have to go, Sal. Bye.
- Lockwood  - 我得走了, Sal, 再见
Doctor Arnold.
Arnold 博士
You'd better send them in.
你最好送他们进去
Charlie, it's me.
Charlie, 是我
- Is it safe? - Yes.
- 安全吗？  - 是的
What happened? Did you call the mainland?
发生了什么？你给大陆打电话了吗？
Did the police take the vicar away?
What's...
警察把牧师带走了吗？什么...
It's all right.
没事的
Everything's going to be all right.
一起都会好起来的
You see, Charlie?
你看, Charlie?
Everything's going to be all right.
一起都会好起来的
Oh, my God.
噢, 上帝
I have a new member for our congregation.
我有一个新成员介绍给大家
Thank you, Daron.
谢谢你, Daron
- There's no need to be afraid, Charlie.
- Who the hell are you?
- 没有必要害怕, Charlie  - 你到底是什么鬼？
What are you doing here, you murdering.
你在这里做什么, 你在谋杀啊
What have you done to Daron?
你把 Daron 怎么了？
A strong young mind.
一个强大而年轻的大脑
Just what we need.
正是我们需要的
Some do resist more than others.
有些人比其他人更抵触
Personally, I blame it on your
rather expensive university education.
就我个人来说, 我觉得应该责怪你那昂贵的大学教育
No simple faith.
没有了朴素的信念
You see?
你明白吗？
You can't fight it.
你没法抵抗它
This is something far older
than mankind itself.
这是比人类自身还要古老的东西
It's been waiting.
它一直在等待
Now it's calling to you for help,
现在它在呼唤着你的帮助
and you won't want to refuse.
而你不想要拒绝
Beautiful, isn't it?
很漂亮, 对不对
- Seems quiet enough.  - Well?
- 感觉太安静了  - 怎样？
- What do you think?
- I think this is Colonel Wilson's show,
- 你怎么想？  - 我觉得这是 Wilson 上校的戏
and you, Miss Alexander,
are his scientific advisor.
而你, Alexander 小姐, 是他的科学顾问
I'm only here at Geneva's insistence.
我只是因为日内瓦坚持才来这里的
Ramsay, have the pilot drop anchor,
Ramsay, 让导航员抛锚
get the men on deck and
prepare the dinghies.
把人叫到甲板上来, 准备好登陆小艇
Sir.
是
Let us pray.
我们祈祷吧
Don't tell me.
不要告诉我
You've a feeling we're being watched.
你感觉到了, 我们正被人监视着
Ramsay, take one man and scout ahead.
Ramsay, 带一个人去前面侦察
- Stay in contact.  - Sir.
- 保持联系  - 是
Hargreaves, you're with me.
Hargreaves, 你跟我来
The soldiers must not interfere.
不能让士兵来干扰
Greyhound One to Greyhound Leader.
灰狗一号呼叫灰狗队长
Greyhound Leader. Go ahead.
我是灰狗队长, 继续前进
No sign of anything suspicious.
没有任何可疑迹象
Steep incline ahead.
前方有陡坡
Heavy woodland on top.
上面出现茂密树林
Band of the Coldstream Guards
could be in there for all we know.
我们都知道，冷溪卫队军乐团可能就在上面
All right, Greyhound One.
好的, 灰狗一号
Find a way up but exercise extreme caution.
找一条路上去, 但千万小心
We have entered woodland
and will hold this position. Over.
我们已经进入树林, 暂时保持这个位置．完毕
Take cover.
隐蔽
Lockwood!
Lockwood!﻿
What is it?
怎么了？
Autons.
有 Auton
Greyhound One. Greyhound One.
灰狗一号, 灰狗一号
What's happening, over?
什么情况．完毕
Greyhound Leader.
灰狗队长
Autons firing from cover.
Auton 躲在暗处开枪
Hargreaves is dead.
Hargreaves 死了
Request covering fire.
请求火力掩护
This is Greyhound Leader to all Greyhounds.
Covering fire.
灰狗队长呼叫所有灰狗, 火力掩护
火力掩护
Cease fire. Cease fire.
停火, 听火
Are you all right, Ramsay?
你没事吧, Ramsay?
Just like old times, Lockwood.
老样子, Lockwoord
What's the situation, Sergeant?
情况怎么样, 中士?
They can see us.
他们能看见我们
We can't see them.
我们看不见他们
They've got us pinned down.
他们把我们包围了
We must assess the strength of their force.
我们必须评估他们的火力强度
Do not allow them to leave.
别让他们跑了
Leave her.
别管她
- She's not important now.
- I have to go to her.
- 她现在不重要   - 我必须去找她
You've experienced the rapture.
你已经经历了大欢喜
You belong with us now.
你是我们的一员了
No.
不
We can't make it back to the boat,
they'll cut us down.
我们没法回到船上去了, 他们把后路切断了
We need reinforcements.
我们需要增援
This is Greyhound Leader to Broadsword.
这里是灰狗队长呼叫腰刀
Greyhound Leader calling Broadsword.
灰狗队长呼叫腰刀
Urgent assistance required.
需要紧急援助
Do you read me?
你能听到吗？
You're wasting your time, Colonel.
你在浪费时间, 上校
The last thing they're going to let us do
is call for the cavalry.
他们最不想让我们干的事情, 就是呼叫增援
The AT36.
用 AT36
Let's show them we mean business.
让他们看看, 我们是来真的
Davis, prepare the AT36.
Davis, 准备 AT36
- Do we know if this thing works?
- Precisely.
- 我们知道这东西能否管用吧？  - 清楚
It's strange they haven't moved in
for the kill yet.
很奇怪的是，他们没有冲过来猛杀一通
All we need now is a target.
我们现在需要的是找到目标
Greyhound Four reports movement, sir.
灰狗四号报告，长官
Stand by.
待命
Peek-a-boo, you plastic bastard.
躲-猫-猫, 你个塑料杂种
Davis, fire.
Davis, 开火
Yes!
是！
This isn't solving anything.
这解决不了任何问题
We've got to find some answers.
我们必须找到答案
Haven't you got any?
你一点没有吗？
You knew they'd be here.
你知道他们会来
Yes, I suppose I did.
是的, 我觉得我知道
Autons are controlled
by the Nestene Consciousness.
Auton 是被 Nestene 意识体控制的
We know a damaged fragment of that escaped
我们知道有一部分逃走了
from a top security warehouse two years ago.
两年前从一个最高机密的仓库逃走的
That fragment, that creature,
must be on this island.
那一部分, 那个怪物, 肯定在这个岛上
If we can find out what it's doing here,
we might at least be half-way to stopping it.
如果我们能搞明白它在做什么, 我们可能至少成功了一半
At the moment, we're falling
right into its trap
目前而言, 我们正落入了它的陷阱
by participating in a pointless
shoot-out we can't win.
陷在了这个不得要领、无法取胜的枪战里
All quiet on the Western Front.
西线无战事
It seems they're not intending to
annihilate us.
看起来他们无疑全歼我们
What is it?
怎么了？
Lockwood!
Lockwood!﻿
Sir.
长官
Where the hell are they going?
见鬼他们这是去哪里？
- Ramsay, get them back here.
- Yes, sir.
- Ramsay, 把他们弄回来  - 是, 长官
What the hell are you doing?
你们这是在做什么？
This place is crawling with Autons.
这个地方到处都是 Auton
- One of the locals.
- Perhaps with some answers.
- 一个本地人  - 也许有一些答案
How did you know?
你怎么知道？
Oh, Lockwood.
噢, Lockwood
Lockwood.
Lockwood﻿
Down!
趴下！
No!
不！
We've got to get out of here.
我们必须得离开这里
The, the church.
那个, 那个教堂
Something...Beneath the church.
有什么东西...在教堂下面
What is it?
什么东西？
They've cut off our retreat.
We can't get back to the others.
他们切断了我们的退路, 我们没法回去找其他人了
Come on.
来吧
Got any more shots in that thing, Davis?
那玩意儿还有多少子弹，Davis？
Three, sir.
三发, 长官
Greyhound Leader to Greyhound One.
灰狗队长呼叫灰狗一号
Where are you? Where are you?
你们在哪里？你们在哪里？
Greyhound Leader, say again.
灰狗队长, 请重复
Heavy interference.
干扰太强了
I'm afraid the signals
it's using to control the Autons...
我担心控制 Auton 的那个信号
...are jamming our transmissions.
...把我们的通讯给阻塞了
It's?
那是...?
Let me get this straight.
我就直接点吧
Are we still dealing with the blob
that got out of the air vents two years ago?
我们在对付的，还是两年前消失在空气中的那坨东西吗？
How did it get here?
它怎么到这里来的？
Your guess is as good as mine.
你的猜想跟我一样
Something beneath the church.
那个教堂下面有什么东西
What?
什么东西？
That's what that girl said, before she died.
就是那个女孩说过的, 在她死之前
What's under the church?
教堂下面有什么东西？
What's the matter?
Can't you read my mind?
什么情况？ 你不是可以读我的思想吗？
The idea of not being in control
really upsets you, doesn't it?
无法掌控事态这一点真的让你不爽, 对不
No. What really upsets me...
不, 真正让我不爽的...
is the idea of being investigated
by the Internal Security Division.
是我发现自己正在被内部安全部调查
You're with the ISD?
你是 ISD 的？
And you're investigating him?
而且你在调查他？
And she's apparently psychic.
她显然是一个通灵者
When that girl looked at you,
那个女孩看着你的时候
she saw whatever she thinks
is under the church here.
她以为她看见的是躲在教堂下面的东西
Wait a minute.
等一下
Why are you investigating Lockwood?
你为什么在调查 Lockwood?
He's UNIT's best operative.
他是 UNIT 最好的特工
We're investigating him because his...
我们在调查他是因为他的...
special abilities...
特殊能力
are a two-way street.
那是一条双行道
Did you think your dreams would be exempt?
你觉得你的梦就是安全港湾吗?
Dreams?
梦？
There must have been a moment of contact,
肯定发生过短暂的接触
when somehow the Nestene Consciousness
has gained a foot-hold in your mind.
不知怎地, Nestene 意识体进入了你的意识
I have to know if it's just taken up lodgings
我得搞清楚它是仅仅寄宿呢
or whether it's the landlord.
还是当起了房东
You're mixing your metaphors.
你的比喻太混乱了
Don't you think we'd better
investigate this church...
你不觉得我们应该查一下这个教堂
before Colonel Wilson is
obliged to make his last stand?
赶在 Wilson 上校被迫展开最后一战之前？
Well, if the church is the centre
of their operations,
是, 如果那个教堂是他们的行动中心
that's where we've got to go.
那就是我们必须要去的地方
We knock out the blob,
we stop the Autons, right?
我们敲掉那坨东西, 就阻止住了 Auton, 对吗？
Right.
对
Come on.
快点
Of course...
当然了...
if I am working for the other side,
如果是为另一方工作
I may not even be aware of it.
我也许自己都没有意识到
Had you thought of that one, Miss Alexander?
你考虑过这个可能吗, Alexander 小姐？
Oh, yes.
噢, 是的
Ramsay... I want you to go back,
Ramsay... 我要你现在回去
get Wilson and the rest of the men.
找到 Wilson 和其他人
No way.
不行
Don't argue...
别争论...
Just go.
走吧
What is it?
怎么了?
Come on.
快点
Lockwood.
Lockwood﻿
UNIT's creature.
UNIT 的怪物
At last.
终于
O come, all ye faithful.
噢, 来吧, 信念鉴定的人
Well?
怎样？
Sense of...
感受到一种...
Joy...
喜悦...
Overwhelming rapture.
不胜之喜
Then there's confusion...
还有迷惑...
And loss...
和失落...
And fear.
和恐惧
Oh, well, that explains everything.
噢, 好吧, 这就解释了一切
Thank you.
谢谢你
Perhaps if you hadn't shut yourself
away
all your life,
也许如果你不是一辈子都把自己封闭起来
obsessed by your own uniqueness,
痴迷于你自己的独特性
you might be able to admit
some of those things yourself.
你也许自己也能承认其中的一些事情
I've seen them...
我见过他们...
In black and white.
是黑白的
Maybe if you could be honest with yourself
也许, 如果你对自己诚实一点
we might find out what the
Nestene Consciousness is trying to achieve.
我们就有可能搞明白，Nestene 意识体想要达到什么目的
What's the matter...
怎么了？
No sarcastic come-back at the ready?
不冷嘲热讽地怼回来了？
No.
不
You've been betrayed by
your own people, Lockwood,
你被自己人背叛了, Lockwood
treated as an outsider.
被当作了一个外人
But for the first time in your life,
但在你生命中, 第一次...
you feel as if you belong to...
你觉得你好像是属于...
Something.
某个东西
I think this is the moment when
you make a run for it, Miss Alexander.
我觉得到了你开跑的时刻了, Alexander 小姐
Don't say I didn't warn you.
别说我没警告你
Why have you brought me here?
你为什么带我来这里
Oh, I think you know.
噢，我想你知道
You should have left
when you had the chance.
你刚才有机会的时候就该走的
I'm keeping an eye on you.
我盯着你呢
Your leaving was not an option...
你没有离开这个选项...
Natasha Alexander.
Natasha Alexander.﻿
In your own way, you might be
as helpful to us as Lockwood.
虽然方式不同，但你对我们跟 Lockwood 一样有用
What do you mean?
你什么意思？
Our good people of the island here...
这个岛上的这些好人们...
are as devoted to us as they can be,
尽他们可能侍奉我们
but their mental energies are,
但他们的精神能量
without exception I'm afraid,
rather modest.
恐怕没有例外，都很平常
It's been a long, laborious job,
这是个漫长而辛苦的工作
but we're nearly there.
但我们快完成了
All we need now is...
我们现在所需要的是...
a little push...
一个小小的推动...
from your...
来自你那...
excellently nurtured mental powers,
Miss Alexander...
精心培育的精神力量，Alexander 小姐...
And Lockwood's special knowledge.
还有 Lockwood 的特殊知识
And what special knowledge would that be?
这说的是什么特殊知识？
Still resisting.
还在抵抗
Very commendable, Lockwood...
非常难得，Lockwood...
but pointless.
但毫无意义
When we last met,
上次我们碰面的时候
a seed was planted in your mind.
就将一颗种子种在了你的意识里
Your very...
你那非常..
very special mind, Lockwood.
非常特别的意识，Lockwood
You're too kind.
你太善良了
It's been...germinating...
它一直在...发芽...
and you don't want to stop it...
而你不想阻止它...
Do you?
是吧？
What's under this church?
这个教堂下面有什么？
What has always been...
它一直就在这里...
since long before the dawn of Mankind.
早在人类黎明之前
As Lockwood will tell you,
we have been...
正如 Lockwood 会告诉你的，我们已经...
colonising other planets...
殖民了好几个星球...
for a thousand million years.
统治了数十亿年
We Nestenes visited this world...
我们 Nestene 到访了这个星球...
and many others...
和其它多个星球...
long before intelligent life evolved.
早在进化出智慧生命之前
We made...
我们做了...
investments...
投资...
for the future.
为着未来
Consequently, this ground
has always been...
于是，这片土地就一直被...
feared...
害怕着...
revered...
尊敬着...
worshipped!
崇拜着
Many of these sites do survive,
很多据点都幸存下来了
but none so perfectly intact...
但没有一个完美...
as this.
如此
Lockwood, you've got to listen to me.
Lockwood, 你必须听我说
He belongs to us now.
他现在属于我们了
And so will you.
而你也快了
We are awakening one of
the surviving Nestene creatures.
我们正在唤醒一个幸存的 Nestene 生物
A beacon waiting to be ignited.
一座等着被点亮的灯塔
Through it we shall bring the entire...
通过它我们将把整个...
Nestene Consciousness to Earth.
Nestene 意识体带来地球
Opposition will be... impossible
作对将是...不可能的
Lockwood, can't you see what you're doing?
Lockwood, 你不明白自己在做什么吗？
With Lockwood's knowledge of
all UNIT's plans for combating alien invasion...
UNIT 打击外星人入侵的所有计划， Lockwood 全都了解
we will be...
凭借着这个，我们将...
invincible.
所向披靡
No!
不！
You said it would be me leading the prayer.
你说过将会是我来领导信徒的
That I would bring him back to us.
说过我将把他带回到我们中间
Are you all right?
你没事吧
We've succeeded, Lockwood.
我们成功了，Lockwood
It won't be long before
contact is established.
过不了多久联系就会建立起来
The entire Nestene Consciousness?
整个 Nestene 意识体吗？
Lockwood, you've got to stop it.
Lockwood，你必须阻止它
They're uploading every scrap
of information you have access to.
他们正在上传你能访问的每一片信息
You're going to leave the
Earth open to invasion.
你这会让地球很容易被入侵
They'll destroy us all!
他们会毁灭我们所有人的！
But not Lockwood.
但 Lockwood 不会
He'll live on in the Consciousness.
他将活在意识体里
He'll belong.
他将属于
He's nothing in common with you...
他跟你们没有什么共同点...
Or the rest of your race.
跟你们种族其他人也是
What the hell happened here?
这里到底发生了什么？
Get down.
趴下
Davis, prepare to give
it your last shot.
Davis，准备射出你最后的子弹
Don't shoot. Don't shoot.
别开枪，别开枪！
Sergeant, where the
hell have you been?
中士，你到底都去哪儿了？
We've got to move fast, sir.
我们必须得赶紧走，长官
Lockwood and Natasha are in trouble.
Lockwood 和 Natasha 有麻烦了
They can't be.
他们不可能
What sort of trouble?
什么样的麻烦？
That kind of trouble.
那样的麻烦
Listen to me,
you stubborn old bastard.
听我说，你个顽固的老东西
Don't let that smooth-talking
piece of plastic
别让那个巧舌如簧的塑料假人
lead you wallow in self-pity.
引导你沉溺于自怜中
Look into my mind.
进入我的意识看看
I know what it's like
to be the outsider...
我知道当一个局外人是什么样的...
but we make ourselves outsiders.
但那是我们自己让自己成为局外人
The trick is to let people in.
关键是要让别人进来
Lockwood, I'm letting you in.
Lockwood，我让你进来
You've got to stop...
你必须要阻止...
What have you done?
你做了什么？
What have I done?
我做了什么？
You're not off the hook yet.
你还别想甩掉我
I haven't finished my investigation.
我还没有完成调查
- All right?  - Thank you.
- 还好吧？  - 谢谢你
Have you finished your investigation?
完成你的调查了吗？
No.
没
I'll leave you to it, then.
那，我就不打扰了
He's the soul of discretion.
他挺会审时度势
Where did that creature go?
那个生物去了哪里？
It hasn't gone, has it?
它还没走，是吧？
Lockwood, what have you done?
Lockwood，你做了什么？
Whose side are you on?
你到底是哪边的？